Before I start answering the questions, I
would like to point out some important things.
So, for example, what is happening here with
this transition G is that we are going directly
from two to nine.
This means, yes, we are activating this composite
state D, this whole thing here.
But we are not going into the start state
which is ten, but rather we're going directly
into nine.
So, in comparison, this transition is doing
an explicit entry.
While this transition, for example, E is not
doing an explicit entry, it's doing a standard
entry, because it's going to the D as a whole.
And then the decision becomes that we start
with the starting state, which is ten.
The general structure of this diagram is that
we have these states, A, B, C, D, these are
composite states.
The biggest one is a that contains everything,
of course, everything except for this part
here.
And then inside A we have two big composite
states, which are D and B. And then inside
B we have smaller composite states, which
are E and C. And this composite state C is
divided into two regions by this line.
I think now we are ready to start answering
the questions.
Question A. With which state or states does
the diagram start?
The answer is six and three.
Since the fork explicitly jumps to the states
at the beginning, this is the fork we are
talking about.
This is the starting state.
It's in the outside of A which is as I said,
it's the biggest state, the composite state
that contains almost everything here.
So, this fork is going directly into B. And
from B, it's going directly into C. And from
C it's going to this state three.
And here it's doing the same and it's going
into state six.
Question B. Name all possible states or combinations
of states from which C can be left.
The answer is leaving C is possible in these
combinations of states, six and five, six
and four, six and three, or seven and four.
These are four states, four state combinations.
But actually, they result from two possibilities.
The first one is to exit through this state,
which is a joint state.
The second possibility is to exit with the
help of this transition, e. And when you exit
with e, it doesn't matter where you are, it
doesn't matter where which state you are currently
in here.
This is why you have six with five, six with
four and six with three.
Next question.
Which state or states result from leaving
C from seven?
This is seven and four.
This is four, if the previously last visited
state in D was eight, which is this one.
The answer is ten.
Since the entry happens via the start state
of D. But why?
This happens because here it says we leave
C from seven and four.
This means we do this transition d, and this
transition d is not pointing at any inner state
of D. It's just pointing at D as a whole.
And since there is no history state in D,
we just go where the start state is pointing
at, which is state ten.
Next question says, which state or states
result from leaving D from eight?
This is eight.
If B was previously last left from two, this
is B. And this is two.
The answer is one, because the starting state
of E is what we jump to.
Why do we do that?
Because the history here is a shallow history.
In other words, this shallow history belongs
to the composite state B. So, it remembers
the last state we were at when we left B.
So, it remembers we were at E or at C. And
that's it.
It doesn't look at the inner states one or
two.
Otherwise, it would be a deep history.
So, this history, remember that we left B
from E and not from C. Okay, but where does
it say that here?
It says that here by telling us that B was
previously last left from two and two is contained
in E. Now, let's go into E. And the starting
state points at one.
This means we start with one.
Next question says, does the answer to (d) change
if we change that shallow history state to
a deep history state?
And if so, how?
The answer is yes.
Because as I discussed before, the deep
history would remember exactly which one of those
one or two we were at.
The next question says, what different possibilities
are there to jump to state six when leaving
D?
This is six and this is D.
The answer is there are two possibilities.
The first one is to go from state nine, which
is this one using the transition F. But as
you can see the transition F goes directly
into three, it doesn't point at six at all.
So, how does this get us to six?
Well, the answer is C, this composite state
C is divided into two regions.
And this division into two regions means that
these two parts, these two regions run in
a parallel way.
So, it is not like C is divided into two states.
No, this is still one state.
A good way to think about this is to imagine
going into a house and then inside this house
going into the bathroom.
So, this means you occupy the bathroom.
And we can say that the bathroom is occupied
by you.
So, we say it's active.
But does this mean that you are somehow not
inside the house anymore?
No, it means you are still inside the house.
And it means that the house is occupied by
you.
And the same goes here.
So, when you go into three, the whole C, the
whole state C is now active.
And when state C is active, we have rules
here, we have things that have to be fulfilled,
that have to happen.
It says here we start with five, the state
five and the state six, these are the two
starting states.
Now the second possibility is to go from eight
with the transition i if B, this B, was last
exited from C which is this state here.
Let's see how this works.
Let's say we last exited B from C. So, the
shallow history remembers one thing, which
is that we were in C. As I said before, it
doesn't care which inner state we were at.
So, this means when we go from eight with
i into B, we go into C and with C, we just
start with these two starting states.
And we start with five and six.
And we are done.